Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
So I guess this is it.
Yeah.
I guess so.
Well, do you guys have to go
to the new house right away
or do you have some time?
We got some time.
Okay, should we
get some coffee?
Sure.
Where?
Wow.
I mean, this is beautiful.
It's beautiful.
Look at that.
Oh, man.
So many... So many different
episodes are like
you know,
Lisa playing guitar up there,
Jen and I, our first kiss,
like, the pilot,
opening the umbrella.
I mean, come on.
Yeah.
Where is everyone?
Come on, I want to see everyone.
Oh, my God.
Oh!
That "Oh!"
This is all I care about.
- Hi. Hi.
- Hi.
Oh, my God.
Hello.
Oh, you smell good, too.
Yeah, so do you.
Look at that.
Wasn't there a decision
to lose this?
Yes, I thought this was gone.
This was here in the beginning,
and...
- It kept, like...
- Got in the way.
It got in the way. Yeah.
Sorry, you got lost
behind the beam.
As it's probably
getting in the way now.
- Well, I don't know.
- Oh.
- Sometimes it's a choice.
- There we go.
- Ee, ee, ee.
- How crazy is this?
I hear someone.
I just started crying.
Floosh!
Joo!
It's amazing.
- Hi.
- How are you?
Ooh. Holy crap.
Oh, weird.
Alright, well,
where's the tissue box?
Uh-oh.
- Oh!
- Hey!
What are you guys doing here?
Waiting for you.
Oh, my God.
How are you?
Oh, look at you.
- Look at you.
- Hello. Big blue.
This is great.
This is too weird.
Look at this.
Remember when we all used
to fit through that door?
- Oh.
- I got chills.
It's so weird.
Walk that way, buddy.
Look at this.
Does Courteney still have her
lines written on the table?
Do you know what
the difference is?
You know what's nuts?
Oh, really?
I never knew she did that.
And I saw it.
I was like, "What is this?"
She goes...
"Mind your business," she said.
So before we shot that night,
I erased it all.
- No.
- And she got so mad at me.
Or had the script
in the sink.
- That I do remember.
- That I remember.
There was always
a script in the sink.
- I didn't know why.
- That was Courteney's script.
Good for her.
Oh, my God.
- Really?
- C.C.!
- Did you cry too?
- Yes.
Okay, good.
Of course I did.
How are you? Ohh.
Wow.
I know.
It's worse than you imagine.
- Look at you.
- Oh, you do smell good, Court.
- Hi.
- Oh, my gosh. That's crazy.
- Do you remember that night?
- What?
You had... I don't remember
what episode it was.
But you had this, like,
big speech,
and you were struggling
with it all week long,
and you wrote it on the table,
and then just... and I didn't
know that that's what you did.
And I saw it and I asked you,
and you told me
to mind my business.
So when you weren't looking,
I erased it before we shot.
- That's so mean.
- And you got so mad at me.
I didn't know you did that.
Why would you erase it?
Just to get you.
God, I had so many...
so much of my dialogue
within these apples.
- I didn't know.
- Oh, sometimes, yeah.
I have memory issues.
Matthew Perry's here.
Hello.
- Hey, Matt.
- Matty!
Looshy. Hi.
Could you be any later?
- Hey.
- How are you, brother?
Hey.
- How are you, bud?
- Good.
Look at all of us.
- Oh, my God.
- This is crazy.
Does it seem smaller
to anyone else?
From here to over there.
- Does not feel smaller.
- No.
It feels the same to me.
And was it always purple,
that wall?
- Yes.
- Oh, my God.
Yeah, you've gone crazy.
I mean, this is incredible.
Yeah, it really is.
The whole thing.
Just really...
Oh, the one thing missing...
the original cookie jar
is at Lisa Kudrow's house.
Did you take anything
from the set besides...
I took a neon coffee mug.
I have the original ball
from the foosball table.
You look at it and go,
"What is that old, crappy ..."
Should have taken
the whole table.
We smashed it, remember?
By the end, it got smashed.
- Oh, it did?
- Then what's that?
Well, that was before
it got destroyed.
We're going back
a little further.
I need to watch this series.
- It was good.
- I have the original ball.
- Yeah, yeah.
- It had its moments.
That's what I hear.
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's DOA ♪
♪ It's like you're always stuck
in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been your day,
your week, your month ♪
♪ Or even your year, but ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ When the rain
starts to pour ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ Like I've been there before ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me too ♪
Save it. Thank you.
You're very, very kind.
Okay, thank you so much for
coming out to be here tonight.
Let's be honest,
none of you had other plans.
Have fun, pal.
Okay, here we go.
- We excited? - We got this in the bag.
- We excited?
This is gonna be fun.
...together on a stage
for the first time in years.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Jennifer Aniston,
Courteney Cox,
Lisa Kudrow, David Schwimmer,
Matthew Perry, and Matt LeBlanc,
the cast of "Friends"!
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's DOA ♪
♪ It's like you're always stuck
in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been your day,
your week, your month ♪
♪ Or even your year, but ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me too ♪
The cast of "Friends,"
everybody.
Might need to squeeze up there.
Take a seat.
Look at this.
Look at all of you.
Hello.
Hello, James Corden.
I cannot tell you
how incredible it is
to be here with all of you now.
And we are... I should say
we are shooting now
in front of the iconic fountain
where you shot
the opening credits.
It's beautiful and it's lovely.
It is, however, noisy...
- Yes.
- ...and difficult...
difficult to conduct
an interview.
So if you'll just wait,
watch this.
Watch this for power.
Wait there.
Done. Okay.
That's superpowers.
- Alright. I know. I know.
- Those are superpowers.
You still got it.
- I know.
- Had we known
all those years ago.
Now, how are we doing?
This has been an emotional day
for all of you.
How are you feeling
to be together,
the six of you right now?
It's been so fantastic
and exciting.
And we've literally just
sort of slipped right back
right... as we usually do.
David, how have you
found this time?
Really emotional.
Really, really fun, actually.
I felt, after the initial shock
of just being
in the same room together,
just I think we all just fell
right into our same old...
our same old kind of joking
around like we're a family.
- And so it really was...
- Regressed. We regressed.
- We regressed, yeah.
- Back to 20s.
How much do you
stay in touch?
Yeah, no,
we stay in touch for sure.
- Maybe not every day.
- Sure.
But, you know,
we have such a bond
from having done this show
and forged
this very tight relationship
that, you know,
any time you text
or call someone,
they're going to pick up.
- They'll be there.
- Matthew, who doesn't pick up?
I don't hear from anyone.
Now, I'm going to
give you some stats, okay?
So "Friends," you made
236 episodes of the show.
It aired in
over 220 territories.
"Friends" was TV's number-one
comedy for six straight seasons,
averaging 25 million viewers
a week.
52 million people
watched the finale.
The show has been watched
over 100 billion times
across all platforms.
- And tonight...
- That's a lot.
- ...is a real
celebration of that.
And the creators of the show
are here tonight
sat in the audience.
Marta Kauffman, David Crane,
Kevin Bright are just sat there.
They created the show.
I'm the executive producer
and sometimes director
of "Friends."
My name is Kevin Bright.
I'm co-creator,
executive producer,
and writer Marta Kauffman.
I'm the co-creator and
executive producer of "Friends."
I'm David Crane.
Marta and I spent our 20s
living in New York.
We had a tight
circle of friends.
There we were in our 20s
in New York
trying to make a living
and find love.
And we thought
that could be a show.
We drew on relatives of ours
and friends of ours
and names were...
We named Chandler
after a friend of mine.
I mean, we definitely
pulled from our lives.
We really were intrigued
with the idea
of doing a true ensemble.
It's not like there's a lead
and they have friends.
No, it's just about the friends.
We're following
all of their stories equally,
which we felt like
we hadn't seen before.
The one-sentence pitch is it's
about that time in your life
when your friends
are your family.
- Want to see this area?
- Yeah.
I knew you were
gonna do it.
When did you knock?
Only in the reunion.
Wow-ee.
Oh, the beam is back.
Memories just flashed back
of, like, jokes coming out
of the bathroom.
- I know, the bathroom.
- "Oh, do not ..."
Just, like, stupid things
that you would do.
Oh.
Did you go next door?
- I have not.
- Come on.
What's back here?
Look at the chairs.
The chairs are here.
Ohh, yeah, oh, yeah.
These I think can be operated
by just one person.
But back then,
we had three per camera.
It was a huge crew.
Four cameras, like,
the choreography was incredible.
- Ohhh.
Ohh. Ohh.
Do you remember
the episode where
we never got out of the chairs?
Yeah.
Pizza's on the way.
I told you
we wouldn't have to get up.
But you remember the beginning
of the week
after the table draft,
you came to me and you go,
"It's so stupid."
I was like, "Yeah,
but that's the brilliance."
And you were like, "Maybe
we can have fun with this."
And then we had a blast.
What if we have to pee?
I'll cancel the sodas.
Oh, they're sitting
in their chairs.
No, they aren't.
Are they really?
Oh, Matty,
it's good to see you, man.
This is great.
Schwimmer, the episode where
you guys were throwing a ball
and the whole time,
you couldn't drop the ball.
I don't remember that.
- Let me ask the boys.
- What kind of ball?
It was like a Nerf ball.
Hey, guys.
Hey, do you remember the one
where you guys were throwing
a ball back and forth
- and you couldn't drop the ball?
- Couldn't drop the ball, yeah.
- Yes.
- So it was you two.
Everybody ended up
getting in on it.
- Schwimmer was in on it.
- No memory.
You want to
get something to eat?
Or you want to see how long
we can throw this ball
back and forth?
- The ball thing.
- Yeah?
This is how old we are.
This is what laptops were.
No, I remember that.
It's so heavy.
Let's go look at
the dressing rooms.
- This is Jennifer's forever.
- My room.
Those are my hardwood floors.
You guys ate lunch
together every day.
- Yeah, we did.
- First couple of years,
like, we ate
every meal together.
That's right.
- Even on the weekend.
- We watched every show together.
We were inseparable, all of us.
Big center table here,
and Enger would cook...
It all seems small to me,
the whole stage.
No, that's impossible, though,
because we haven't grown.
- Well, speak for yourself.
- Shut up.
Let's talk about
favorite episodes.
Everybody's got
their favorite episodes.
I'm keen to know what are yours.
I love the Thanksgiving ones,
but I also... I loved
when we traded...
when we lost the apartment.
The quiz, the embryos.
Yeah, the one with the embryos.
Yeah, but that quiz was really
fun and really devastating.
Yeah.
I just can't believe
that you think
that you and Chandler
know me and Rachel better
than we know you.
Well, we do.
What is Monica's
biggest pet peeve?
- Animals dressed as humans.
- That's correct.
What name appears
on the address label?
- It's Chandler Bing!
- No!
Actually,
it's "Miss Chanandler Bond."
If we win, they have to get rid
of the rooster.
- Ooh, that's interesting.
- But if we win...
we get your apartment.
What is Chandler Bing's job?
Oh, oh, he's a transponds...
transponster!
That's not even a word!
- No!
- Oh, my God.
- Yes!
- Whoo!
Okay, the test is ready.
Each team will answer
a set of trivia questions, okay?
The categories are
"Fears and Pet Peeves,"
- "Ancient History"...
- Oh, no!
- ..."Literature"...
- Uh-oh.
- ...and "It's All Relative."
- Okay.
Now the coin toss
to see who goes first.
Okay.
Okay, somebody call it
this time.
- Oh, sorry.
- Okay, here we go.
Okay.
Heads.
Oh, it's tails,
and the boys go first.
Alright. Okay.
Okay, here we go.
Pick your category.
- Ancient History.
- Alright.
"Rachel wrote Ross a letter
and demanded he read it
before they got back together.
How many pages was that letter?"
18 pages.
Damn.
- 18 pages...
- Front and back!
Front and back is correct.
Oh, my God, that's good.
- This is the letter.
- Is that the letter?
This is the letter.
Who gets the points for that?
- What?
- Me.
Okay, ladies, pick a category.
- It's All Relative.
- Alright.
- Yes.
"Ladies, can you name
this voice?"
That's my monkey.
Oh! Mr... Mr. Henkel.
- Mr. Winkel... Hinkel?
- Hinkel.
- Wait. No, no, no. Really?
- No? What's his name?
Wait, wait.
Do it one more time.
Can we hear it again?
We know it. We know it.
No, wait, "That's my monkey."
It's the guy who lives
downstairs.
- And his name would be...?
- Mr. Rickles.
- No.
- I know it. I know it.
I know it!
It's not your turn!
No, will, the mystery voice
please reveal himself?
It's Larry Hankin
back as Mr. Heckles.
Heckles!
I said Larry Hankin.
You all owe me a cat
and a waffle.
Larry Hankin, everyone.
But why didn't I get points
for getting the name right?!
Alright, okay, guys,
you're up.
- Literature.
Oh, that's a good choice,
gentlemen.
- Thank you.
- Literature.
"According to Monica,
how many erogenous zones
- are there on the female body?"
- Seven.
Courteney, Courteney,
is that correct?
That's correct. Seven.
Alright, ladies.
- Ancient History.
Oh, you know what?
I'm... I'm gonna need
a little help
- with this question.
- Oh, dear.
Gentlemen.
- Oh.
- Oh!
"This very barbershop quartet
famously delivered
a message to Rachel from Ross,
but can you
complete the lyrics?"
One, two, three.
♪ Congratulations on
your first week ♪
♪ At your brand-new job ♪
♪ It won't be long
before you're the boss ♪
♪ Oompah, oompah, oompah ♪
♪ And you know who will
be there to support you ♪
♪ Your one and only boyfriend ♪
- Your something.
- Ross.
- It's not Ross?
- Wait.
Is that...
Does that feel right?
Wait, wait. ♪ Your one
and only boyfriend ♪
Gentlemen?
♪ Dah-dah, dah-dah,
boyfriend Ross ♪
boyfriend Ro... ♪
Is that correct, gentlemen?
It's nice to have a boyfriend.
♪ Your loyal, loving boyfriend,
Ross ♪
Ross.
Thanks, guys.
- Thank you.
I think "Friends"
has this magic
because each character
is so distinct
that they could hold
a television show by themselves.
Yes?
Hi. Is Rachel here?
I'm her sister.
When my agent
called me and said,
"Do you want to play
Rachel Green's sister
on 'Friends, '"
I was like,
"Have I won the lottery?"
Which sister is this?
Is this the spoiled one
or the one that bit her?
- Daddy cut me off.
- Never mind. I got it.
Okay, so one of the most
exciting things was I got
to be in this scene
where I'm in the apartment
and Joey walks in and he goes...
Hey, how you doin'?
Don't.
And it was his iconic line
and I was so excited.
And to watch a famous character
say his famous line, come on.
Hey, it's Phoebe.
We can talk to Phoebe.
If you think about Monica
or Phoebe or Rachel,
each one of them
is a leading character.
But together, you get this great
repartee, all the actors
at the top of their game,
and great chemistry.
Alright.
No!
Joey, we swore we'd never tell.
They'll never understand.
We have to say something.
We have to get it out.
It's eating me alive.
They were funny,
they were engaging,
they knew
their characters so well,
but they also worked
so well together.
There was a real sense
of love for each other.
- Monica...
- Bigger, louder.
...got stung by a jellyfish.
Alright.
I got stung.
Stung bad.
I couldn't stand.
I couldn't... I couldn't walk.
We were two miles
from the house.
We were scared and alone.
We didn't think
we could make it.
I was in too much pain.
And I was tired from digging
the huge hole.
And then Joey
remembered something.
I'd seen this thing
on the Discovery Channel.
Wait a minute. I saw that
Yeah.
About jellyfish and how if y...
- Eww.
- Eww!
You... You peed on yourself?
Eww!
You can't say that.
You don't know.
I thought I was gonna
pass out from the pain.
Anyway, I-I tried,
but I couldn't.
I just couldn't bend that way,
so...
- Oh, Monica looks at Joey.
- Eww!
That's right, I stepped up.
She's my friend
and she needed help.
If I had to,
I'd pee on any one of you.
Only, uh, I couldn't.
I got the stage fright.
I wanted to help,
but there was just too much
pressure, so... so I, uh...
I turned to Chandler.
Joey kept screaming at me,
"Do it, do it, do it now."
Sometimes late at night,
I can still hear the screaming.
That... That's 'cause sometimes
I just do it through the wall
to freak you out.
And scene.
You know, I was laughing
in that scene.
Do you remember
the first table read ever?
That's the first time
I laid eyes on any of you.
I don't remember how...
I remember what you wore.
- That's it.
- That's unbelievable.
I don't remember
what the boys wore.
I do remember what Courteney
and you wore.
- That's it.
- What did I wear?
- A white lacy hippie-ish blouse.
- Oh, I was trying to be Phoebe.
You were being Phoebe.
And jeans.
And Courteney had
a pink babydoll tee
from Fred Segal
with a white trim.
Yeah, I just remember
that's when we all met
or I remember meeting everyone
the first time.
You don't remember
what I was wearing?
I don't remember what,
but I do remember
you're the first person I saw.
And I was like, "Oh, okay.
That's why I've been losing out
on all of these roles
over these years.
I mean, this is the good...
this is the hunk.
You know, right here.
Of course he's Joey."
And then hearing all of you
for the first time,
- I... that blew me away.
- That's what I remember.
I just thought everyone
was so perfectly cast.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- That's what I remember.
Casting the show
was really hard,
much more so than
I think we expected it to be.
We saw approximately
a gazillion people.
There are so many
different scenarios
where it wasn't going to be
these six people.
It would have been
such a different show.
We had seen David
for another role
for a pilot
we'd done the year before.
His hangdog expression
stuck with us.
So when we started doing Ross,
that was in our minds.
Try to get David.
David has quit television.
He's had a miserable experience
doing another show.
He's moved back to Chicago
to just do theater.
And we had to beg him
and beseech him.
And "We wrote this for you."
I believe we sent him
gift baskets.
I have no recollection
of the gift basket.
I thought we just
sent him the script.
We assured him that whatever
his past experience was,
this was going to be different,
we promise.
And he... he came on board.
Alright, we got one.
We saw a bunch of women
who read Phoebe,
and it was nothing.
And meanwhile, my husband,
Jeffrey, was writing
and producing on
"Mad About You," and he said,
"Phoebe is right here
playing Ursula the waitress."
Here you go.
- Can I get you anything else?
- No, thanks. We're fine.
Okay, I'm just gonna go
get your check, then.
- Got it right here.
- Great. Okay. Right.
You could see a lot of the
beginnings of Phoebe there,
but on "Mad About You,"
she had more of an edge.
Phoebe was a much more
positive image.
Lisa was someone who came in
and nailed the audition.
She not only did
everything we'd hoped,
she elevated the material.
Lisa Kudrow was
the second one
to get cast in "Friends"
right after David.
And that was at the beginning,
so we thought we were on a roll.
And then came about
two and a half months
where we cast no one.
Matt LeBlanc,
if I remember correctly,
had like $11 in his pocket
when he auditioned.
Maybe it was $9,
but it wasn't a lot.
We saw a lot of guys
who you believed were actors,
guys who liked women,
but they weren't funny.
Then Matt came in and suddenly
on him, the lines felt funny.
He hadn't done an awful lot.
He'd done another show,
but he hadn't done an awful lot.
So Matt went right down
to the wire,
auditioned at the network,
at NBC with another actor,
and he killed it,
and he got the part as Joey.
But the funny thing about it is
the other actor ended up
in the show
in "The One With the Unagi,"
playing Fake Joey, ironically.
How are you doing?
No, no, no, no, no.
How you doin'?
How you doin'? Damn it, Carl.
Go wait in the hall.
What do you remember
about the audition process?
I remember I had gone in
a bunch of times,
and I think it was
on the final callback.
I had gone... I had gone with
a friend of mine to run lines
and he said, you know,
"So the show's about friends
and being friends
with, you know,
just a group of friends?"
I was like, "Yeah, kind of."
He goes, "Then we should
go out drinking."
And I was like, "Yeah,
that's a good idea."
So to make a long story short,
I woke up in the middle
of the night at his apartment
and had to go to the bathroom,
and I got up too fast.
And I can't believe
I'm telling this,
but I kind of blacked out,
as you do,
and fell face first
into the toilet.
And I hit my nose
on the bottom of the toilet seat
and a huge, like, chunk of meat
came off my nose.
And I'm looking in the mirror
and it's bleeding.
I was like, "Oh, my God."
So I have to go in
for the big callback.
And it's like a big,
ugly scab on my nose.
And Marta Kauffman said,
"What happened to your face?"
And I told the truth
and got the job so...
- Look at that.
- Right? That's what happened.
And, David,
I know that at the time,
I think you were... you were
doing a lot of theater.
What was it about "Friends"
that attracted you to it?
Marta and David made it clear
to me, made it known to me
that they had written the role
of Ross with my voice in mind.
And I was like,
"Well, I don't understand."
- Ah, it's a bug. It's a bug.
- Oh, no!
- Is it gone?
- No, it's right there.
Aah! Oh, that's fuzz.
That's fuzz.
That's alright.
Was it real?
- Is it gone?
- It's gone, it's gone.
Can I just say...
The important thing is
that we dealt with it well.
Yeah.
You even reacted to that
like Phoebe.
That was great.
That was much more
entertaining than my story.
It really was.
We were having a tough time
finding Monica,
and we really saw Courteney
as kind of a Rachel at the time.
We met with Courteney Cox,
and she explained to us
why she didn't think
she was a Rachel
and that she herself
was more of a Monica.
And she was right.
Courteney brought this
incredible joy to the character.
She'd been in
the Bruce Springsteen video
and with Michael J. Fox
on "Family Ties."
So people knew Courteney.
Not enough so that it made it
the Courteney Cox show,
which was always the fear.
We didn't want stars.
But everything
Courteney brought to it
made Monica so much richer
than what we had
originally intended.
I thought Chandler was gonna be
the easiest part to cast,
because he's not
just a character.
He's got jokes. He's got,
like, actual real jokes.
So I thought, "Here we go.
This is gonna be great."
And we saw actor after actor,
and it wasn't funny.
We had worked with
Matthew Perry on "Dream On."
And when Matthew reads
that dialogue, it sparkles
and it comes alive.
And for the first time
through the casting process,
we knew there was
a character there
and that this was
the only guy to play it.
There was just
a little problem.
He had already signed on
for another sitcom.
It was about luggage handlers
in the future at LAX.
It just sounded insane.
Enjoy Los Angeles.
By the way, Griffith Park
has the best picnic areas.
Thank you.
You are most insignificant.
And then someone from
Warner Bros. actually was
at the taping of "2194"
and thought
"This show is never going.
Put him in 'Friends.'
We'll be okay."
Suddenly it was like
"There's our Chandler."
And I just won $1 million.
He spins the lines in a way
that they're his.
And there's so many
comedy skills there.
Rachel was the hardest part
to cast,
and it was
the last part we cast.
She could be a really
unlikable character.
I mean, this is an incredibly
selfish, self-involved,
spoiled... in the wrong hands,
you don't like Rachel.
We saw lots and lots
and lots of other women.
Women who come in wearing
actual wedding dresses
and none of it...
You didn't really fall in love,
and you needed to,
'cause you needed to feel
what Ross was feeling.
And then Jennifer came in.
Jennifer had a similar problem
to Matthew in that
she'd already signed on
to a show called
"Muddling Through."
You gonna eat that steak
or argue with it?
Madeline, this here steak
was supposed to be rare.
Gidney, tell me something.
How often do we
have steak on the menu?
Shoot, hardly ever.
That's right.
So what you have there
is a rare steak.
And they had already shot
six episodes of this show,
so it was a little bit more
than just the pilot.
And we took this big risk
to cast her,
share her with this other show
and we'll see who wins.
And we even shot
not only the pilot,
but probably three
episodes of "Friends"
while that show
was still on television.
And if it had...
if CBS had picked it up,
we would have had to reshoot
the first three episodes
of "Friends."
Jennifer had this warmth
and sincerity
and genuineness about her,
where she just made you feel
okay about everything else
that Rachel was
that you might have
passed judgment on.
I was kind of hoping
that wouldn't be an issue.
Thank you.
Cut. Alright.
So, that's right.
So, Matthew and Jen,
you were in another show.
I mean, Jen, what were
your first impressions
of the rest of the cast
when you finally got
to meet them,
when it was made clear
that you could do the show?
Well, first of all, I had
a graveyard of failed pilots.
I did a pilot a year
and I thought,
"That's what you do.
You do a pilot a year
and you have some cash.
And then you go on
to another pilot."
And I just remember sitting
with these five other people
and thinking,
"This is the greatest
group of people,
the greatest script.
I have to do this."
And I actually,
tail between my legs,
hat in hand, went to the
producer of the show I was on
because they hired me
in second position,
and I said, "Please release me
from this show.
I love this show
that I'm doing right now.
Nothing against your show.
I just love these people
and I am having so much fun."
And he said... he goes,
"I-I saw that show.
I'm gonna tell you something.
That show's not gonna
make you a star."
"This show is gonna
- Enough said.
- Well, he's here tonight.
- That producer's here tonight.
- No!
Okay, guys, you're up.
Okay, It's All Relative.
"While in Las Vegas,
Joey finds
his identical hand twin."
Wouldn't you pay good money
to see these identical hands
showcased in some type
of a, uh, entertainment venue?
If you leave now,
I will chop off my hand
and give it to you.
From this lineup...
please identify
Joey's hand twin.
2 or 3.
- I think it's 2.
- You think it's 2?
I think it's 2.
Right there, number 2.
Yes, that is correct.
It's Thomas Lennon, everybody.
Great seeing you guys.
Great seeing you.
Great to see you.
Alright.
Alright, ladies, ladies,
you're up.
- Fears. Fears and Pet Peeves.
- Fears and Pet Peeves.
- Louder, Court.
"Ladies, there's a message
on the answering machine.
Can you identify the voice?"
Matt, can you hit that button?
"Hey, guys, I'm finally
retiring from ophthalmology
and would love for all of you
to come to my retirement party
next week."
- Tom... Oh, sorry.
- Let me know if you can make it.
- Tom Selleck.
Oh, my God.
I didn't say that. Wait.
- You looked so disappointed.
- Well, it's okay.
Will the mystery voice
please make himself known?
How could it not be?
Look who it is.
Tom Selleck, everybody.
Hello.
Do you want to sit for a sec?
- How you doing?
- Good to see you, buddy.
- Wow.
Alright, Tom,
you have a bonus question.
- Alright.
- Oh, God. Okay.
Monica famously chose Chandler
over Richard.
What did Chandler
do for a living?
Oh, my God.
Just think this through.
Think it through.
I say transponster.
No, that's what
we lost the apartment over.
Oh, I thought we never
found out, though.
- Transponster sounds good to me.
- Yes.
Transponster's not right.
That's what I said.
That's not even a word.
And then we lost.
Right. Here's the answer.
And it's...
- Oh, Tom has it.
- Yeah.
Nobody knows, really.
- That's the answer.
- That's what I just said.
Hey, that's the answer.
Yeah, that is the answer.
I think that should
go to the girls, then.
- I do too.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
They didn't have... No, no, no.
Yeah, yeah,
we said nobody knows.
And the girls are the winners.
Obviously, the show came out
and immediately resonated
with people.
When did you start to feel like
those changes
that you'd been told about
were starting...
the world
was starting to change?
- The summer.
- It was... Yeah.
When we came back
for a second season,
it was a completely
different ballgame.
I think people were starting
to say, "Hey,"
and you were not...
you were scared.
And "What do you want?"
And at first, it's very jarring.
No one really prepares you for
what that's going to be like.
I remember one time I was...
It was middle of the week,
I guess it was, I don't remember
what day of the week.
Doesn't matter.
It goes Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday.
Yeah, that part I know.
But it was... I was...
I happened to have the news on,
and on the TV,
they had the screen split
into six boxes.
And it was an aerial shot,
live, of each of our houses.
Oh, geez.
And I remember looking at it
going "What the ..."
and I could hear the helicopter
over my house.
I was like, "What the hell?"
And I'm looking close at the
screen, and my roof is a mess.
So when the helicopter
flew away,
I got the ladder out
and went up on the roof
and sure as shit, I've got
some leaks up there.
I had to call the roofer and
have them come over and fix it.
The fact is,
like, no one was going through
what we were going through
except the other five.
So I think that was really...
So there's no shoulders
outside of this group
to sort of go,
"Oh, this is so ..."
And I think
it kind of created...
imprinted in
our neural pathways
this sort of, like,
we are actually family.
Yeah. Because our family
couldn't relate.
Our friends, our closest friends
- They were there for us, I think.
- Your family could...
My family was more starstruck
about it than we were.
But the only other people who
really knew what it was like
were the other five.
It seemed like
you weren't getting...
We were doing a show,
and we were working really hard.
But it wasn't until I was
walking through the airport...
I don't remember
where I was going...
but they were on every magazine.
And I was like, "Whoa.
Holy shit. This is crazy."
The theme song became a hit
on a radio station.
And when I heard that
on my car one day,
that was like, "Wow, this is not
your average television show."
They're on the cover
of Rolling Stone.
Rolling Stone.
I mean, we're a TV show.
They've somehow entered
the zeitgeist.
I don't know when that happened.
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
Jennifer is gorgeous.
Why is it such a phenomenon?
It just suits her very well.
It's spectacular.
I think my favorite was
I was dropping my kids off,
and my rabbi stopped me and
asked me about Ross and Rachel
and when they were gonna
get together
and how that's gonna happen.
Wherever we were,
suddenly there are
thousands of people gathered.
It's like the Beatles
were there.
Everybody was screaming
and yelling
and behind barricades.
- It was crazy.
- Bye!
Once "Friends" had gone global,
I think we were in
18 different languages.
Basically any place I went,
you know, from Jordan to India,
they knew what "Friends" was.
My mom bought me the DVDs
of the whole series
when I was in elementary school.
"Friends" really had a big hand
in teaching me English,
and the show
really taught me the things
about life and true friendship.
We love "Friends."
Ohh.
Could I be wearing
any more clothes?
My eyes! My eyes!
Pervert! Pervert!
Shut up! Shut up!
♪ Smelly cat, smelly cat ♪
♪ What are they feeding you? ♪
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Yeah, noisy boys.
We became fans of "Friends"
when we were in first year
in college.
We were too shy
to talk to girls,
so "Friends" was a way
to boost our morale
and boost our confidence
and be able to make new friends,
especially ladies.
Yeah, baby.
My most favorite episode
on "Friends" is the episode
in which Monica asks Chandler
to marry her.
After seeing that,
I knew that is the way
I wanted to ask my soul mate
and my husband to marry me,
and that's exactly what I did.
I'm a single mom,
and, you know, society pushes us
to marry the first guy who does
say, "Will you marry me?"
But I mean, as a woman, you have
to take control of your life.
So watching that episode
got me thinking
that I can also take charge
of my own relationship.
We're engaged!
I was battling depression.
I was at a very dark place.
One week, I wouldn't go out.
The need to even eat
was a problem.
I wouldn't eat.
I was a gay man who wanted to
have hair like Jennifer Aniston.
So you can imagine how lonely
I sometimes felt.
And "Friends" was
what I came home to.
"Friends" was...
They were my friends
since I didn't really have any.
And, um... I can't.
It became a reason
for me to wake up every day
because I felt
I had friends around me.
Like every Chandler,
I found my Monica.
I'm gonna cry.
That's so nice.
They have no idea
the kind of impact they
partially made in this world,
so when they sleep,
they should relax
knowing that
they have saved more lives,
even if they don't know them.
I am one.
And for those who don't like
the show, just, uh...
I think you're like Joey 100%,
because you just walk
into my room
with these jokes
that don't make sense.
- They are funny.
- But you are howling.
Like, you have tears
coming out of your eyes.
They're always funny.
So, yeah, I think you're Joey
with a hint of Phoebe.
Vee loves "Friends."
And I realize what, like,
this true addiction
to a TV show means.
- We watched it together as well.
- And then I got you hooked.
Yes, and that was
my proudest moment.
When I got her hooked on it,
I was like,
"Mission accomplished."
And then we'd stay up all night
watching it together.
You know, "Friends"
brought friends together.
Okay, everyone, gather up.
One of my favorite moments
from "Friends" is the routine,
and that's the show
where Ross and Monica
want to perform
their favorite dance.
I know what'll get us up
on a platform.
- What?
- The routine.
The routine.
Five, six, seven, eight.
♪ Boys, the trouble with ♪
♪ Boys, the troubles with,
boys ♪
♪ They're nothing but trouble ♪
♪ Boys, the trouble with ♪
♪ Boys, the troubles with,
boys ♪
♪ They're nothing but trouble ♪
♪ They'll make you think
they've got a halo above them ♪
♪ But boys are trouble ♪
♪ Trouble is all of them ♪
♪ Boys, the trouble with ♪
♪ Boys, the troubles with,
boys ♪
♪ They're nothing but trouble ♪
♪ Boys, the trouble with ♪
♪ Boys, the troubles with,
boys ♪
It's on the end.
Now, throughout tonight,
we're gonna take questions
from the audience.
There's a lot of fans here.
Has anybody got a question
tonight
for the cast of "Friends"?
Yes, there's a lady right here.
Yes. What's your question?
So, "Friends" was obviously
amazing for all of you,
but was there anything
that you didn't like?
Way to keep it positive.
Was there anything
that you didn't like
while you were shooting
the show?
- The monkey.
- And the monkey.
- Oh, the monkey.
- Not Marcel. Really?
- The monkey scared me.
- I loved the monkey.
David was not a fan.
Yeah, 'cause you didn't
have to touch it.
- What? I did too.
- Yeah, she did. She did.
Eh. See...
First of all, I want to say
I love animals.
I love primates.
I have nothing against animals.
I'm an animal lover.
However, I'm...
Here was my problem.
Like, the monkey,
obviously, it was trained
and it had to hit its mark
and do its thing right at the,
you know, at the perfect time.
But what inevitably
began to happen
was we would
all have choreographed,
like, bits kind of timed out,
and it would get messed up
because the monkey
didn't do its job right.
So we'd have to... we'd have
to... we'd have to reset.
We'd have to go again
because the monkey
- didn't get it right.
- David's so angry still.
So this kept happening
over and over
where we're about to do
something really funny.
But the monkey
didn't hit its mark,
so we have to start again.
I would like you to be
more serious about this.
That combined... See, you
didn't have to deal with it.
And that combined with
when the monkey was resting
and just waiting for,
you know, for us to roll,
it would sit on my shoulder
and the trainer would come up
and just open and give... give
the monkey live grubs to eat.
So the monkey... the monkey
would be sitting on my shoulder,
take some grubs...
take some grubs,
like, break them in half,
these squirming, live...
then eat it, and then he'd just
go like that.
So I'd have monkey grubby hands
all over, all over.
And it just wasn't... it was...
it was time for Marcel to...
...to off, you know?
I got to say, great question.
You really threw up
some good answers there.
Alright. Okay. Let's go...
I think
we've got another question.
Yes. There's a couple here
in the audience here.
Do you have a question?
Yes, I do.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's Mr. and Mrs. Geller.
Christina Pickles
and Elliott Gould, everybody.
Yay!
Eliot, Christina,
I'm keen to know,
what do you remember
about that time?
I remember they were
awfully nice to us.
Very down-to-earth,
real people.
We loved it
because they loved us.
And one day we came to work
and they said,
"The parents are here,
the parents are here."
And it was so moving.
And we really did feel
like their parents.
In fact, we used to worry
about them quite a lot.
And Elliott said to me,
"We're behaving like
we're really their parents,"
and we really did feel we were
because they're so sweet.
- We love you.
- That's incredibly sweet.
Thank you so much
for being here tonight.
Fantastic.
I'd have to say,
I'm most like Monica
because I'm a clean freak.
You know, I travel a lot
and I'm always in hotels.
I've always got downtime.
When I'm missing the kids,
when I'm missing the family,
I put on "Friends"
because it makes me smile.
Orange juice
and what looks like cider.
My favorite episode has to be
where they're all getting ready
in the apartment.
It's fat. I drank fat.
Ross is hurrying everyone up
because he has a huge speech
to make, and he's nervous.
- Why aren't you guys dressed?
- We have a half-hour.
When Chandler
goes to the toilet,
Joey sits in Chandler's chair,
and then he comes back
and it all escalates.
- You're in my seat.
- How is this your seat?
- Because I was sitting there.
- But then you left.
Well, it's not like
I went to Spain.
Joey eventually
gives up his seat,
but he takes the cushions
with him.
What are you doing?
Well, you said I had
to give you the chair.
You didn't say anything
about the cushions.
The cushions are the essence
of the chair.
That's right.
I'm taking the essence.
It's one of those episodes
that when I'm away
and when I'm feeling
a little bit low,
I just put it on
and it makes me smile
to almost the point of crying.
You hide my clothes,
I'm wearing everything you own.
- Oh, my God.
- Look at me, I'm Chandler.
Could I be wearing
any more clothes?
Maybe if I wasn't
going commando.
"The One Where Nobody's Ready,"
it's the first episode
we ever did that's shot
in real time like a play.
I'll tell you, it's hot
with all this stuff on.
I better not do any,
I don't know, lunges.
Some of that was you had
to do some bottle shows.
You had to do shows that weren't
gonna cost a fortune
and keep them located
just on our sets
without building new sets,
without, you know.
So how do you make a story where
you put everybody in one room?
What were you doing when
your arm came out of the socket?
- Oh.
- Shoulder.
That was when he and I
were fighting over the chair.
That was one of
the best episodes we ever did.
- Oh, oh, I remember.
- Okay, you tell it.
- Firemen.
- Yeah.
There were firemen
in the episode.
- No.
- No? I'm sorry.
There were firemen on the set.
No, Warner Bros.
fire department
came in to help Joey.
I'm sorry. I take it back.
But go ahead
and announce that again.
That's the best moment
I've had in months.
Chandler and Joey have been
fighting over this chair,
and Joey runs
and jumps into the chair.
We shot it three times,
and it went perfectly.
Lord knows why we had
to shoot it a fourth time.
You want to go for me
sitting on Matty's lap?
And I went just to jump
over the coffee table
- and somehow tripped.
- Oh, God.
And my legs
went up in the air
and my shoulder
came out of the socket.
Are we gonna watch this?
His arm getting pulled out?
- Oh, here it is.
- Oh, shit.
I don't want to see pain.
It doesn't look like anything
till I stand up.
Okay, okay.
Action.
Oh, no!
Ow, ow, ow.
It happened right there?
- Yeah.
- Did it already happen?
- Shit.
Ohh.
Oh, are you pulling on it?
Are you pulling the wrong arm?
- No, it's the other one.
- It's the other one.
No, no, no, no,
it's going down too far.
Oh, shit.
Okay, Gretchen?
Just a moment, please.
- Should we cut?
- Ow!
- Ohh.
- Are you for real?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, 'cause he dislocated his shoulder.
- 'Cause it hurt.
Oh, I thought someone tried
to pull on it.
Jesus.
Cut.
So in come all the paramedics
and whatever,
and they've got to take him
to the hospital.
And so that was the end
of filming
because it wasn't
even an episode
we're like, "Well, we can
shoot out the other scenes."
No, it happened to be
on the one episode
where it's just the six of them,
they're all in it,
and we're done for the night.
And the way...
do you remember how
the sling was written
into the show?
- No.
- Oh.
Whoa!
See, Joe,
that's why your parents told you
not to jump on the bed.
So we had to put that
into the show,
but we waited
until he was okay again
to film the ending of "The One
Where No One Was Ready."
Did you tell the doctor
you did it
- jumping up and down on your bed?
- No.
So what started out to be
the simplest "Friends" episode
ended up taking the longest
amount of time to shoot.
There was one thing
that we did every show
that we didn't do that night
before we started.
- Our huddle.
- Mm-hmm.
- We didn't do it that night.
- We didn't do the huddle.
We didn't do it?
That's the one time
we didn't do it.
- Why didn't we do it?
- I don't know.
That's right, 'cause we were
sort of like,
"You know what?
We're taking too long.
The audience has been waiting.
Let's just go."
I think that's why
we didn't do it.
- Really?
- Well, it was sort of early on.
- It wasn't like...
- It was very early on.
And then after that,
we were like,
"Do we need to do the huddle?"
- And he'd say, "Yeah."
- Yeah, we do.
"'Cause I don't want anything
else falling off me."
- Yeah.
- We do need to do the huddle.
After that, we always did it.
Let's go see where
we did the huddle.
Right here. Let's go.
Straight down
to this purple door.
We did the huddle right here.
- Yeah.
- Right around here.
Come on, let's do a huddle.
Come on.
Wait. You mean we...
So the atmosphere on tape night
was always crackling.
There was a lot of energy.
It was exciting.
You're putting on a show.
It was a fun night,
but it was a really hard
working night for us
and we would listen
to the audience.
And if a joke didn't land,
even if we loved that joke,
they were telling us
it's not good enough.
So we would put our heads
together and try to beat it.
It's a buffet.
It's in trouble.
It's in trouble,
like I'm gonna go eat it all.
How about "Here's where I win
all my money back"?
I like that. Great.
Kevin, there's a lot
of changes coming.
- Good shit.
- You guys ready?
Where is the waitress?
I'm starving.
It's a buffet, man.
Oh, here's where I win
all my money back.
I really enjoyed the energy
of the audience, though.
- I mean, the live audience.
- Oh, yeah.
- I mean...
- I did, too.
It's like doing a one-act play
every week with all of us.
I found myself, like,
when they would laugh
at something,
I would think to myself,
"Oh, if you think that's funny,
when till you get a load
of this next line."
They would challenge me
to try even...
I felt this rewarding feeling.
- Or not. Or a flat nothing.
- I'm coming over here.
- I feel left out over there.
- Sit here.
At least to me,
I felt like I was gonna die
if they didn't laugh.
And it's not healthy for sure.
But I would sometimes
say a line,
and they wouldn't laugh,
and I would sweat
and... and just, like,
go into convulsions.
If I didn't get the laugh
I was supposed to get,
- I would freak out.
- It would take you down.
- You didn't tell us that.
- No?
No, I don't remember you
ever saying that.
Oh, yeah, I felt like that
every single night.
One of the times we listened
to the audience the most
was when we were
shooting in London
and Monica and Chandler
are in bed together.
Action.
I'm getting married today!
Morning, Ross.
I'm getting married!
- A-whoo-hoo!
- Whoo-hoo!
Do you think
he knew I was here?
The audience went insane.
We were just standing there
going "This is insane."
We just let them go.
Okay, your turn.
No, I'm kidding.
- Cut!
- He told me to say it.
He did.
I think that moment
was the beginning
of how we rethought
Monica and Chandler,
'cause the original plan was
they would sleep together
in London,
it was a brief thing,
and we'd have some fun
with it afterward
as they're both like,
"Oh, my God, what did we do?"
But the way
the audience reacted,
we realized there's more to this
and we need to pay attention.
Well, I've never done that
with you before.
That was the end
of the season,
so we had time to really
ruminate and think about it,
but it was
such a powerful moment
that we knew
we had to explore it more.
We expanded it from just
a "one night in London" thing
to "this could be a thing"
thing.
I'm still on London time.
Does that count?
- Oh, that counts.
- Oh, good.
We still, at that point,
didn't quite realize
how far it would go.
We still thought maybe it'd be
fun with them doing it in secret
and hiding it, which did give us
a lot of funny stuff.
Hey, it's me. Coming in.
I've had a very long, hard day.
I love the episode where
they've just returned home
from London
and Monica and Chandler
are trying to keep it a secret
that they've been hooking up.
So thanks for having me over.
The cast,
they know how powerful
just, like, a funny visual
set piece will be,
and it's funnier than anything
they could have ever said.
Rach.
Phoebs.
See ya.
So the really great thing
about "Friends"
- is they're so good with farce.
- What the hell was that?
So when there's a secret like
Monica and Chandler are dating,
it's so fun
because we the audience knows,
but none of the rest
of the cast knows.
Okay, this is from "The One
Where Everyone Finds Out."
Ugly naked guy's apartment.
Phoebe and Rachel have
tagged along with Ross.
Although it's pretty empty,
it's a great place.
Oh, my God.
I love this apartment.
Isn't it perfect?
I can't believe I never
realized how... how great it is.
Well, that is because
your eye immediately
- goes to the big naked man.
- It's amazing.
You better hurry up
and fill out an application,
or I'm gonna beat you to it.
Ohh.
- That's sort of how you did it.
- Is that?
Well, I never thought
I'd say this,
but, um, I'm gonna go use
ugly naked guy's bathroom.
She exits.
Phoebe looks out the window.
Oh, look,
there's Monica and Chandler.
Hey! Hey, you guys! Hey!
Chandler and Monica
are standing close together.
They start taking off
each other's clothes.
Phoebe's mind is totally blown.
Oh! Oh!
Chandler and Monica!
Rachel sees
what Phoebe is seeing.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Chandler and Monica!
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Oh! My eyes! My eyes!
- I know.
Phoebe, Phoebe, Phoebe,
Phoebs, Phoebe.
- Oh!
- It's okay. It's okay.
- It's okay.
- They're doing it!
I know. I know.
I actually know.
- I know I know.
- You know?
I do. I know. And Joey knows.
But Ross doesn't know.
So you have to stop screaming.
What's going on?
- What, what?
- Nothing.
Oh, God, we're just so excited
that you might
get this apartment.
Actually,
it looks really good.
Get in here. Come on.
Get in here. Hug it out.
Hug it out. Hug it out.
Oh, my God.
Alright.
Yeah, don't get too excited.
I haven't done this
in a long time.
So I should be Phoebe for this.
Okay.
♪ Smelly cat, smelly cat ♪
♪ What are they feeding you? ♪
♪ It's not your fault ♪
♪ They won't take you
to the vet ♪
♪ You're obviously not
their favorite pet ♪
♪ You may not be
a bed of roses ♪
♪ And you're no friend
of those with noses ♪
Hi.
It's so weird, 'cause
I was walking down the street
- and I just happen to have my...
- Guitar.
- Yeah.
- Oh, my God.
- You need some help?
- Yeah, I mean, I think so.
I love "Smelly Cat."
It's one of my favorite songs.
- Oh, my God.
- You mind if I...
- Oh, please.
- ...take "Smelly Cat"
for a spin?
- Yeah, that would be great.
- Alright.
♪ Smelly cat, smelly cat ♪
♪ What are they feeding you? ♪
♪ It's not your fault ♪
That was not bad.
Not... Was it okay?
Um, yeah, yeah, it was really,
really good.
Thank you so much.
♪ They won't take you
to the vet ♪
♪ You're obviously not
their favorite pet ♪
♪ You may not be
a bed of roses ♪
♪ And you're no friend
of those with noses ♪
♪ Smelly cat, smelly cat ♪
♪ What are they feeding you? ♪
♪ It's not your fault ♪
♪ Smelly, smelly, smelly,
really bad, smelly, smelly cat ♪
♪ It's not your fault ♪
♪ Smelly, smelly, smelly,
really bad, smelly, smelly cat ♪
♪ It's not your fault ♪
♪ Smelly cat, smelly cat ♪
♪ What are they feeding you? ♪
♪ It's not your fault ♪
♪ Smelly cat, smelly cat ♪
♪ What are they feeding you? ♪
♪ It's not your fault ♪
Yeah. That's right.
No, but thank you. Thank you.
This was so great.
I still think it's better
when it's just me.
It is.
Oh, you heard it.
Can I just say something?
Thank you so much
for being the person
for all of us on "Friends"
that was the... I don't know if
this is the right way to say it,
but the different one or the one
that was really herself.
Thank you. And thanks for
carrying it along.
- I'm gonna start crying.
- Yeah.
There are seasons
I've never seen.
- Me too.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- I've seen them all.
I've seen every episode.
I would imagine
I've seen them all.
Michel and I started watching
some of Season 4,
which I thought I had watched.
It's as if I didn't.
Do you enjoy them
when you watch them?
He enjoys them more than I do
'cause I'm mortified
with myself.
- Why?
- I don't know.
- You're so good.
Like Lisa, I hadn't seen it
really in 17 years
until my daughter just started
watching it this past year.
And that kind of
sucked me into it.
For me when I watch it,
it's... I'm...
it's hard to watch myself,
but I feel that way
about anything I do
because I don't believe
the acting that I'm doing,
because I know it's not true,
'cause it was me doing it.
That's what you do
for a living.
No, I know, but it's weird
to look at myself.
I'm like,
"I don't buy a word of it."
It's really weird.
But to watch you guys, I was
just so proud to be on the show.
It's just some of the stuff
is so great.
Yeah.
When I do watch the episodes,
I'm laughing out loud
once in every scene
because you all make me
laugh so hard.
That thing
with the leather pants.
Oh, my God. That's still...
That was on the other day.
I just happened to be
in the kitchen with Maureen
and we were eating dinner
and "Friends" is on.
And I'm like, "Oh, look at that.
Let's see which one it is."
And it happened to be the one
with the leather pants.
And I said to my daughter,
"Watch this.
This is funny. Watch David."
And it was really,
really, really funny.
Every little thing,
like pulling the pants up
and, like, slipping and smacking
yourself in the head.
And I know you.
It was all so calculated.
Nothing happens
by accident with you.
I've watched you put things
together and it was brilliant.
I can't quite
be specific about which one,
but I know I'm part
of the Geller family.
I'm incredibly anal,
I'm neurotic as hell,
and I wear
overly tight trousers.
Whoa.
I think one of the reasons
"Friends" is so funny
is the fact that
these six actors
are masters of physical comedy.
- Ohh.
There's a scene
with David Schwimmer
where Ross has decided
not to pay for
the delivery service of a sofa,
and they start taking the couch
up the stairs
and quite quickly,
everyone gets into trouble.
This is not something that's
gonna go up the stairs.
Turn.
I don't think we can turn
anymore.
And David Schwimmer
starts telling them to pivot.
Here we go, pivot.
Pivot.
Pivot!
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
The thing about
that scene is it's so simple.
If you were to see it
on the page initially,
it's three actors carrying
a couch up the stairwell.
There's maybe
a page of dialogue,
and nothing really in that
dialogue suggests
anything massively comic.
But what they do in that time
in carrying
that couch up those stairs
is one of the funniest things
I've seen on TV.
Okay. Here we go.
Pivot!
Alright, let's cut.
Remember our marks?
Do you remember
what color you were?
- Yellow.
- Blue.
- You're blue?
- I don't... I never looked down.
I always used the corner...
- You looked.
- I used the corner...
You tripped every time.
You wouldn't look.
Wait, what happened?
I don't remember you tripping.
The big... yeah.
He ran in,
he looked at his mark...
- No, I tripped on that.
- He tripped.
- He just fell...
- Every single time.
- And I ran.
- You ran as fast as you could.
But the second time I came in
and looked like this.
I went like this the second
time. I came running.
Phoebs, check it out, check it
out, check it out, check it out.
Phoebs, check it out.
The third time, I went
to pull the chair over,
and the chair fell over.
Phoebs, check it out, check it
out, check it out, check it out.
Jesus.
Sorry.
And the final time, you came in.
Because I was like,
"Somebody is getting a laugh.
I can't handle it.
I need to get... I need
to get a laugh too."
Phoebs, Phoebs.
Check it out, check it out,
check it out, check it out.
Oh, Soap Opera Digest.
Oh, no.
That yeti is one smooth talker.
Yetis are smooth talkers.
That's why, um...
Oh, these are bloopers?
That yeti is one smooth talker.
Yetis are smooth talkers.
That's why you never see
any pictures.
He cannot play
at our wedding.
Everyone will leave.
It'll be like when he rapped
at my "butt" mitzvah.
Your "butt" mitzvah?
Thank you.
What?
How can you keep
straight a face?
How much do you have
that's good?
- None.
- None of it? Okay.
I can't belie...
Oh, I just looked right at you.
I'm so sorry.
Action.
I can't believe
Emma's still asleep.
I know.
What are we going to do?
Ha-ha, I win.
The is that?
Ready?
Ha-ha, I win!
What is that?
That's fire,
you jagoff.
The game's over.
Take off your robe.
Okay, I mean...
- No!
Do not take it off.
That was his idea.
Matty, that was your idea.
You remember that?
She carries that
tray to the doctor
because if she doesn't,
people die.
Oh, no.
Lisa, your laugh.
Oh, my God.
No, it's the greatest thing
in the world.
It's the most infectious laugh
- It's so cute.
- The most infectious sound.
The bloopers were so funny.
When you look back,
who had the loudest laugh?
Who had the loud...
Oh, really?
- Lisa.
- Really, Lisa Kudrow?
- You had the loudest.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- The best laugh.
- I can't help it.
- The most enjoyable laugh ever.
- Oh, when Lisa laughs...
Oh, my God.
I can't believe
you didn't say me.
Maggie Wheeler, everybody.
It's Janice.
Mwah.
How are you?
Maggie Wheeler.
Maggie, if you perch
on the corner here,
Jen, you come back in,
everyone shift up.
Maggie, if you perch
in here for us.
Thank you for being here,
Maggie.
What an absolute thrill.
Let's talk about Janice
for a moment.
Where... Where did...
Where did Janice come from?
You know, I got the audition
sides across my fax machine,
and it said
"fast-talking New Yorker,"
and I thought, you know,
I know her.
I-I grew up there.
I-I just... She lives in me.
That's it.
You love me, Chandler Bing.
Oh, no, I don't.
You seek me out.
Something deep in your soul
calls out to me like a foghorn.
Janice, Janice.
You want me, you need me,
you can't live without me.
Matthew Perry is so funny.
And the minute I set eyes on him
and he opened his mouth,
I thought, "Oh, God,
I'm gonna lose it.
I'm gonna crack up.
This character needs a laugh
because I'm not gonna be able
to get through a single scene
with this guy."
And I just looked at him,
and I went
And that was it.
It was just born in the moment.
Thank you, Matthew,
for inspiring that.
Anyway, everybody, oh, my God.
The "Friends" reunion.
- And I get to be a part of it.
- Maggie Wheeler, everybody.
Thank you so much.
Bless you.
Maggie Wheeler, everybody.
What about that?
What a treat.
Oh, I love her.
Now, I should say
there was somebody very,
very special involved
in the show
who couldn't be here tonight
but so desperately wanted
to be part of the show,
he's joining us
on Zoom right now.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
welcome James Michael Tyler.
He's here.
It's Gunther.
Gunther himself, everybody!
He's here.
Hey, what's up, everybody?
How are you?
Good to see you.
You all look great.
Tell us about your experience
making the show
and how your character
just came to life
over the course
of these seasons.
It was the most memorable
10 years of my life, honestly.
I could not have imagined
just a better experience.
All these guys were fantastic.
It was just a joy
to work with them.
I felt very, very special.
- Rachel?
- Yeah?
When's your birthday?
May 5th. Why?
Oh, I-I'm just making a list
of people's birthdays.
- Oh, mine's December...
- Yeah, whatever.
Ladies and gentlemen,
James Michael Tyler,
Gunther himself.
Thanks.
I mean, will you allow me
to ask
what I would consider
to be a cheeky question?
It's impossible not to realize
and see that you were all young,
hot, good-looking,
successful actors.
And it's inconceivable to me
that there weren't
perhaps off-screen romances.
Well, I mean, David?
Yeah.
- Yeah, I mean, the...
- The first season.
Yeah, the first season, we...
I had a major crush on Jen.
- I...
- It was reciprocated.
And I think we both
at some point,
we were both crushing hard
on each other,
but it was like
two ships passing
because one of us
was always in a relationship.
So... And we never crossed
that boundary.
You know, we respected that.
- And... but we both...
- Bullshit.
No, no.
No.
I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
I'm kidding.
It's true. It's true.
Honestly, I remember
saying one time to David,
"It's going to be such a bummer
if the first time you and I
actually kiss is gonna be
on national television."
Sure enough,
first time we kissed
- was in that coffee shop.
- Hang on, so...
But so we just channeled
all of our adoration and love
for each other
into Ross and Rachel.
Is this blowing
anyone else's mind?
Wait. Hang on.
That scene in the coffee house
when their first kiss,
I mean, that was like...
I watched it the other day,
and I was weeping.
The tension,
it was just palpable.
The... It was just perfect.
I'm so glad you guys didn't
because I don't know...
well, you would've
just been great actors.
- But, man, that was something.
- Yeah, we were really
just not great actors.
Interior, coffee house
late that night.
Rachel's putting up chairs.
Ross enters agitated.
- Hi.
- I didn't get a cat.
Oh. That's interesting.
No, no, it's not interesting,
okay?
It's very, very not interesting.
It's actually 100% completely
the opposite of interesting.
Alright. Alright.
I get it, Ross.
You had no right to tell me
you ever had feelings for me.
- What?
- I was doing great with Julie
before I found out about you.
Hey, I was doing great
You think it's easy for me
to see you with Julie?
Well, then you should have
said something before I met her.
I didn't know then.
And how come you
never said anything to me?
There was never a good time.
Right,
because you only had a year
and we only hung out
every night.
Not... Not every night.
You know, and it's not like
I didn't...
I didn't try, Rachel,
but things got in the way,
you know, like...
like Italian guys
or, uh, ex-fiancés,
or... or... or Italian guys.
Hey, there was one Italian guy,
okay?
And do you even have a point?
Yeah, the point is, I-I don't
need this right now, okay?
It's too late.
I'm with somebody else.
Okay? I'm happy.
This ship has sailed.
Okay, so what are you saying?
You can just sort of
put away feelings
or whatever the hell it was
that you felt for me?
Hey, I've been doing it
since the ninth grade.
I've gotten
pretty damn good at it.
Alright, fine.
You go ahead and you do that.
Alright, Ross?
'Cause I don't need
your stupid ship.
- Good.
And you know what?
Now I got closure.
He storms out.
Furious, Rachel locks the three
locks on the front door.
Then she stops, leans on
a table and drops her head.
When she looks up,
she's startled to see Ross
at the door staring back at her.
They hold each other's gaze.
She steps slowly towards
the door, then more quickly,
she unlocks the first lock,
the second, the third,
and then goes to pull
the door open.
Try... Try the bottom one.
The door flies open,
Ross rushes in, grabs her,
and they kiss.
Yay!
- Ohh.
- That was good.
I thought back on the very
first year or two, you know,
when we had breaks
from rehearsal,
like, there were moments
we would, like, cuddle
on a couch or something.
We would spoon
and fall asleep on the couch.
And I'm thinking,
"How did not everyone know
we had... were crushing
on each other?"
We knew. We knew.
Yeah, we knew for sure.
Great. Now. Thanks.
It was a situation
that we couldn't...
we couldn't
do anything about it.
How great, though,
ultimately,
'cause if you had
and it didn't work out,
it would not have
probably been as great.
I'm gonna go down
and ask each of you,
and this is just a simple
yes or no answer.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Were Ross and Rachel on a break?
- Absolutely. Yes.
- Yes.
Yeah, we were on a break.
Yeah.
We had amazing guest stars
on our show.
Couldn't believe
all these people
that we were all
massive fans of.
- Yeah.
- We had Danny DeVito.
Did someone call
for the long arm of the law?
- Oh, my God, was he funny.
- Oh, that was so funny.
- I remember... Oh, my gosh.
- Ben Stiller.
Ben.
One of our biggest laughs ever.
Remember when Ben...
when we went over there?
What are you quacking about?
Ooh, quack, quack, Donald Dodo.
"You chickadee,
you little chickadoo."
It was so funny.
I don't know
why it was so funny.
- 'Cause he's funny.
- 'Cause of Ben Stiller.
- And Julia Roberts.
- Julia Roberts.
- That's right.
- And who enjoyed Julia Roberts?
Come on.
- Your fella Brad.
- Pitt came, did one.
Rachel Green.
God, I hate her, Ross.
I hate her.
And, of course, we had
one of my idols, Sean Penn.
Aren't you gonna
give me a kiss?
Okay, I will.
But right after, you have to
tell me who the hell you are.
And then we get the script
and, of course,
I realize that "Oh,
I'm a... I'm a potato."
- Hey.
Oh, 'cause it was
the Halloween episode.
So I had no...
like very little,
if any, dialogue with him.
But here I'm thinking
"Greatest actor in the world,
and I'm a potato.
I'm a potato."
Oh, my God. You're Sputnik.
Yes.
Marry her.
Now, there's been some
incredibly memorable outfits
and costumes over the 10 seasons
of "Friends,"
and we thought we'd take a look
at some of those iconic costumes
right here tonight
with our very own
"Friends" reunion fashion show.
Cue the music.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome to the stage
Cara Delevingne.
Cara is modeling
Rachel's bridesmaid dress
from Barry and Mindy's wedding
in Season 2.
- Look at that.
- Yes.
As far as
bridesmaid dresses go,
it's actually quite understated.
Modeling Ross's leather pants
from Season 5,
it's Cindy Crawford.
Yeah!
These are Ross's
incredibly tight pants,
but once he got them on,
he couldn't get them off again,
and I think we've all
been there.
It's Sputnik time,
and I know when
you think of Sputnik,
you think of the one,
the only Justin Bieber.
- What?
It's part Russian satellite,
part potato.
Look at that. Justin Bieber,
ladies and gentlemen.
It's astonishing that he's even
managed to make that look cool.
And next up, perhaps the most
famous look of them all,
it's Santa's half-Jewish friend.
It's the Holiday Armadillo.
Cara Delevingne,
ladies and gentlemen,
as the Holiday Armadillo.
Oh, my God. That's amazing.
Whoo!
This surely is a high point
in her modeling career.
- Yeah, baby.
- Work it, work it!
That's amazing.
And, ladies and gentlemen,
wearing all of
Chandler's clothes,
it's Matt LeBlanc!
How did you do that?
You are so cute.
Oh, my God.
Could he be wearing
any more clothes?
Yeah, Matty!
The "Friends" finale
and their farewell party.
Tonight, the cast
is taping the last episode
of their historic sitcom.
Here I am
on the set of "Friends"
in Monica
and Chandler's apartment,
where in just hours, the show
that made TV must-see must end.
If the show was about
that time in your life
when your friends
are your family,
once you have family
of your own,
it's no longer that time.
So the show came,
I think, to a natural end.
It was really important for us
to end everyone in a good place.
We wanted to know
that Monica and Chandler
were gonna have their babies.
Hey.
- Hi.
And that Phoebe was gonna
be happy and had a life.
I want one.
Oh, yeah?
Well, tell me which one.
I'll try to slip it in my coat.
There was some discussion
in the writers room
about do we really want
Ross and Rachel to get together?
- Rachel?
- I'm so sorry.
And we discussed perhaps
sort of ambivalent endings
where it seemed like
down the...
and we went,
"No, this is 'Friends.'
People have been
waiting 10 years
to see this couple get together.
We've got to give them
what they want.
We just have to find
a way to do it
so the journey is unexpected."
Isn't there any way that you
could just let me off the...
No! No!
Oh, my God.
Did she get off the plane?
Did she get off the plane?!
I got off the plane.
Cut!
The night itself was
very difficult to get through.
I really wanted to savor
every minute of it.
I knew it was going to end,
and I didn't want it to end.
Adiós, arrivederci, au revoir.
Take one, five cameras.
Okay, should we
get some coffee?
Sure.
Okay.
Where?
And cut.
The minute it was over...
Marta and I looked
at each other,
and I just kind of
went to pieces.
Yeah, there was a lot of crying
that night.
I don't know how we got
through actual scenes.
I remember that moment,
all of us up
at the end of the hall there.
That was nice.
It was, like, private.
Yeah.
I feel emotional about it now
that I think about it.
It was not just the end
of a series.
It was the end of 10 years
of relationships.
I mean, we were really,
really proud of the show,
but like anything good,
it's sad when it's over.
That night, right after
I called wrap...
Cut.
...the sets immediately started
to be taken down
because there was a pilot
that was coming into
the stage the next day.
That last day,
seeing them strike the set,
it's like seeing someone
pack up your childhood home.
It's gone.
We ended up with
an impromptu party
where everybody just stayed
on set and sat there,
and we ordered pizza and beer,
people signed the flats,
and it was an incredibly
lovely, moving night.
Did we all sign this
at the end?
- Oh, we all signed this.
- Wendy.
- Oh.
- Carlos!
Oh, there's mine.
- What?
- What is it?
"I shit here."
That's right.
I knew it!
Of course that's you.
"The best 10 years of my life.
- Love to all."
- That's me.
- Oh, yeah.
- That's nice.
That is nice.
- Marika!
- Not as nice as mine.
No.
We're here now,
all six of you.
Lisa, has it crossed
your mind about, you know,
well, maybe we could
do another episode,
maybe we could do a movie?
Is that something
you'd ever even contemplate?
No, no.
I'm sorry. I haven't.
No, because that's
all up to Marta and David,
and I once heard them say,
and I completely agree,
that they ended the show
very nicely.
Everyone's lives are very nice,
and they would have to unravel
all those good things in order
for there to be stories.
And, yeah, I don't want anyone's
happy ending unraveled.
Yeah.
Also at my age to be, say, like,
floopy, stop.
- You have to grow up.
- Well, let me ask you this.
Where do you think your
characters would be today?
Where's Rachel?
Rachel. Rachel... I think
we're... did we get married?
- Let's say we got married.
- Sure.
Okay.
I think we ended up getting
married, and we had some kids.
- Kids, yeah.
- And you still played
- with bones.
- Still playing with bones.
Playing with bones, and...
That's paleontology.
Paleontology,
still a paleontologist.
It gets Joey every time.
I don't know why.
Playing with bones.
Playing with the bones.
So you guys are together.
You're happy.
- You've got kids.
- Yes.
Where are Monica and Chandler?
I think my character, Monica,
is still really competitive.
Her kids are probably
not even in... you know,
they're probably graduated.
But she still is in charge
of the bake sale
at, you know,
an elementary school.
She's just got
to keep things going.
PTA, you know.
And you are making me
laugh every day.
I just wanted to make sure
I factored in there somewhere.
And what's Phoebe doing?
Phoebe's married to Mike.
They're probably in Connecticut.
They had kids.
And I think she was like
the advocate for her kids,
who were a little different
and all the other kids
who were just a little
different, you know?
Creating the arts program and
the music thing and all that.
Yeah.
And where's Joey?
I think he probably opened
a sandwich shop in Venice Beach.
Oh!
Oh, I wish he would.
- I wish he would
- Why not?
I wish he would.
Here's Courteney Cox.
My sister on the show.
Honest, this will
really make me cry,
but this will be the last time
that we're ever asked
about the show as a group,
that we will do this.
Like, we're not going to
do this again in 15 more years.
I'll tell you one thing.
We are not waiting
so long to have a dinner.
No, we're not. We will not wait
that long to get together.
I have really enjoyed today.
I really have.
I didn't know, like, kind of
what to expect coming into this.
I knew it was going
to be awesome
to see these five people.
What I did not take into account
was being back on the set...
- No.
- ...and in this environment.
And it's... it's...
it's pretty cool.
Yeah.
Just please also state that
I don't cry like this
when we get together
and have dinners.
Yeah, no. Jen never cries.
No, I...
I mean, it was
an incredible time.
Everything came together.
We became best friends who...
just the chemistry,
the whole thing.
It was life-changing,
and it forever will be.
Not just for us,
but for people who watch it.
And that's just such a great
feeling to carry forever.
I'm really thankful,
and I love you guys so much.
I love you so much.
- It's Courteney?
- It's Courteney.
The best way that I can
describe it is
after the show was over,
at a party or any kind of
social gathering, if one of
us bumped into each other,
that was it,
that was the end of the night.
- You just...
- Sat with that person.
...sat with the person
all night long.
That's true. I remember.
And that was it.
You apologized to
the people you were with,
but they had to understand you
had met somebody special to you
and you were going to talk
to that person
for the rest of the night.
- And that's the way...
- I'm not laughing, I'm crying
- because it's so true.
- That's the way it worked.
It's certainly the way it works
with all of us.
It's just the way it is.
Mm-hmm.
I'm going to cry now.
Good.
I've got a piece of a Kleenex.
Thanks. I'll take it.
It's been COVID tested.
Thank you. I'll take it.
COVID tested?
COVID tested.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the cast of "Friends."
♪ So no one told you life
was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's DOA ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month
or even your year, but ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too ♪
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull